Finding Aid for the John Clough Papers, circa 1959-2002
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
John Clough Papers, circa 1959-2002
Mus. Arc. 14
Clough, John (John L.)
17 boxes (407 folders)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Chiefly secondary materials such as articles and symposium papers collected by John Clough, many with correspondence.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of John Clough, 2003.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
John Clough was born in Dover, Delaware in 1930. He graduated from Dover High School in 1947, earned his bachelor's degree in music at Oberlin College Conservatory of Music and earned his Master's degree in music at Yale University in 1955. He taught at Oberlin 1955-70 and at the University of Michigan 1970-81. He was the Slee Professor of Music Theory at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York from 1981 until his retirement in 2002.
John Clough was one of the major music theorists during the second half of the twentieth century. He produced two music theory text books: Scales, Intervals, Keys, and Triads (1964; expanded edition, 1983; 3rd edition, 1999) and Basic Harmonic Progressions (1984). Clough was also the author of at least eighteen published articles, seven published reviews, and more than two dozen conference papers and lectures. He served as editor of Music Theory Spectrum 1985-55 and on the editorial boards of The Journal of Music Theory and Music Theory Online. His special area of expertise was the interaction of music and mathematics. His influence in the field of music theory extends beyond his own research and findings. He also shaped the field through his teaching and support he demonstrated for the work of other colleagues.
John Clough died September 3, 2003 in Knoxville, Tennessee.
Scope and Content Note
The collection comprises 407 folders in 17 boxes. The majority of the material (296 folders) consists of writings by authors in the field in which John Clough specialized: mathematics as it applies to music. Many of the articles and papers are accompanied by notes or correspondence by John Clough or other scholars. The group of scholars represented in the collection includes noted music theorists, Etyan Agmon, Jay Rahn, David Lewin, David Clampitt, Stephen Soderberg, Jack Douthett, Charles J. Smith, Norman Carey, John Chalmers, Richard Cohn, and many others. The collection also includes Clough's own writings, research notes, and musical analyses.
Correspondence in the collection is almost entirely work-related and very subject-specific. Therefore, correspondence located with articles was left with the article rather than creating a separate correspondence series. Folders that contain only correspondence have been placed in the same series with articles by other authors. These correspondence folders are placed before any other folders of items by the same author. As a result, it is important to note that correspondence by any single author may be scattered throughout many folders in the collection. John Clough's original subject-oriented arrangement was deemed more significant than collation by personal name.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in nine series, with subseries as indicated:
I. Personal documents
II. Writings
A. Articles and lectures
B. Writings with others
C. Analyses: pre-20th century
D. Analyses: 20th century
III. Research notes
IV. Articles and papers by other authors
V. Subject and conference files
VI. Grant applications
VII. Publications
VIII. Bibliographies
IX. Annotated books
Container List
- Personal Documents, circa 1990, I.; Folder 1
  - Résumé, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Writings, 1979-2002, II.; Folder 2-52
  - Articles and lectures (some with commentary by others), 1979-2002, II.A; Folders 2-16
    Arranged alphabetically by title. Some folders contain notes and correspondence with others.
    - Aspects of diatonic sets In Journal of Music Theory, 23:1, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chord personality profiles: the exclusion relation, Lecture, 17 March 1981, with notes, illustrations, and notes (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Diatonic interval sets, Commentary from Jay Rahn (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diatonic interval sets and transformational structures, Reprint from Perspectives of New Music Fall-Winter 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Diatonic trichords in two pieces from Kurtág's Kafka-Fragmente: a neo-Riemannian approach, Offprint from Studia Musicologica Academiae Scientarium Hungaricae 43:3-4, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - An example of diatonic hierarchy in Beethoven's Symphony no. 5 in C minor, second movement, Lecture, 30 April 1981, University at Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Game of triad, Originally housed in Folder 15 with Some unstudied diatonic structures in classical music (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Interval circles, Lecture, 2 May 1990, University at Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Motivic shape in the late string quartets of Beethoven, Typescript with annotations, January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Music and mathematics, Lecture, 11 March 1980, University of Michigan (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Music and mathematics: some recent connections, Lecture, 24 February 1994, Mt. Holyoke College (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - A new theorem of the diatonic set, Lecture, with illustrations and annotations, 25 April 1984, University at Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Scale theory, finger exercises, and ear training, Lecture, 31 October 1987, Music Teachers' National Association Meeting, Buffalo (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Some unstudied diatonic structures in classical music (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Examples only
    - Trichords and transformations in two pieces from György Kurtág's Kafka-Fragments, Version of paper presented at Buffalo Symposium on Neo-Riemannian Theory, 20-21 July 2001, with notes, examples, and correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings with others, 1981-2000, II.B; Folder 17-21
    Arranged alphabetically by co-author names, then by title. Some folders contain notes or correspondence.
    - Douthett, Jack Hyperscales and the generalized tetrachord (Box 1, Folder 17)
      The article itself is not included. Two readers' reports and notes. The article was published in Journal of Music Theory 41:1, Spring 1997.
    - Douthett, Jack Maximally even sets (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Includes version presented in October 1989, with examples and notes.
    - Douthett, Jack, and Krantz, Richard Maximally even sets: a discovery in mathematical music theory is found to apply in physics (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Different versions of the text, with older title, Music, mathematics, and magnetic ordering. Includes correspondence and notes for revisions, 1996-2000.
    - Ehrenkreutz, Stefan Diatonic hierarchies in tonal music (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Partial draft, with examples for 29 October 1981 presentation, notes, and correspondence.
    - Myerson, Gerald Variety and multiplicity in diatonic systems (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Includes preliminary form under Clough's name alone, titled Chord structure and multiplicity in embedded diatonic systems. Also submitted as Musical scales and the generalized circle of fifths to American Mathematical Monthly, a version for scientists.
  - Analyses: pre-20th century, undated, II.C; Folder 22-31
    Arranged alphabetically by name of composer, with miscellaneous folder at end of sequence.
    - 18th century counterpoint (chiefly Johann Sebastian Bach) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Brahms, Johannes (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chopin, Frédéric (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Haydn, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Schubert, Franz (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Schumann, Robert (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Wagner, Richard (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Pre-20th century miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Analyses: 20th century, undated, II.D; Folder 32-52
    - Babbitt, Milton (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Barber, Samuel (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bartók, Béla (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Berg, Alban (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Capers, Valerie (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Coltrane, John (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Dallapiccola, Luigi (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Hindemith, Paul (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Messiaen, Olivier (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Reich, Steve (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold - General (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold - Op. 33a, 33b (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold - Moses und Aron (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Stravinsky, Igor (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Webern, Anton von - Op. 22 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Webern, Anton von - Op. 24 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Webern, Anton von - Op. 29 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Webern, Anton von - Collected (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 20th century - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Research notes, 1959-1999, III.; Folders 53-71
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Extent of contents varies, including articles, clippings, notes, and correspondence.
  - Change ringing (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Articles by Arthur White
  - Concentric circle problem (Box 5, Folder 54)
    6 leaves, no date
  - Diatonic interval cycles and hierarchical structure (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Reviews of Clough's article, notes, and correspondence with Jay Rahn, David Lewin, Gerald Myerson, 1989-1990
  - Indian scales (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Notes and correspondence with Jack Douthett, Lewis Rowell
  - Indian scales, part 2 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Articles by Lewis Rowell: How universal is the idea of mode? Evidence from Asia; Scale and mode in ancient Tamil music literature; The origin of the Indian 22-tone system by Mieczyslaw Kolinski (1961); Pitch-class techniques, the pure fifth, and the East Indian grama family by Jack Douthett (Aug. 1982) With notes by John Clough, correspondence with Jack Douthett, Lewis Rowell, and Jay Rahn
  - Kurtág research (Box 5, Folder 58)
    Notes, clippings, articles, and correspondence
  - Long-range plans, etc. (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Microtonality (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Collection of articles and papers by Chris Mohr, John Chalmers, Richard Sanford, and Jim Horton
  - Music and mathematics, etc. (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Correspondence with David Clampitt and Jack Douthett, 1988-1991
  - Number theory at University of Michigan (Box 5, Folder 62)
    March 1979 issue of Research News: Pure mathematics: problems and prospects in number theory
  - Positional evenness (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Projects in diatonic theory and evenness (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Research notes 1 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Research notes 2 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Research notes - Summer 1959 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Scales, sets, and interval cycles: a taxonomy (Box 6, Folder 68)
    Residual notes for article printed in Music Theory Spectrum 21:1, Spring 1999
  - Science and art (Box 6, Folder 69)
    Clippings
  - Set theory - miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Wong proof (x set); Clough proof (hex theorem) (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Articles and papers by other authors, 1960-2000, IV.; Folders 72-368
  Arranged alphabetically by author names. Folders containing only correspondence are filed before other entries for an author. Many articles or papers also include correspondence specifically related to that paper. Some folders contain only the handouts or examples used with a presentation rather than the entire paper. Papers by unidentified authors are at the end of the sequence, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    Correspondence, 14 items
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    Categories and prototypes in music: diatonic intonation and functional harmony. Handout Paper for Society for Music Theory 15th Annual Meeting
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    A mathematical model of the diatonic system, In Journal of Music Theory 33:1, 1989. Incomplete photocopy of typescript, two printed copies, and comments.
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    Music theory as a cognitive science: some conceptual and methodological issues, In Music Perception 7:3, Spring 1990
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    Towards a diatonic theory of intonation. Two versions: Photocopy of typescript, presented at meeting of the European Society for the Cognitive Science of Music, Oct. 1991; Reprint from Interface 22, 1993.
  - Agmon, Etyan, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    When formal truths are intuitively problematic: inversional equivalence, distance, and the normed space.
  - Agmon, Etyan and Ramat-Gan, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    Linear transformations between cyclically generated chords, In Musikometria 3, 1991
  - Ahn, So-Yung, circa 2002 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    Dissertation materials
  - Alegant, Brian, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    Correspondence and notes
  - Alegant, Brian, undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
    Generalizing twelve-tone combinatoriality
  - Alegant, Brian, undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
    Programs for the enumeration and analysis of twelve-tone mosaics
  - Alegant, Brian, undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
    Six of one half a dozen of the other: partitions and Milton Babbitt's Sextets
  - Alegant, Brian, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    When even becomes odd: a partitional approach to inversion. Paper Paper for Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1996
  - Alegant, Brian and McLean, Don, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    On the nature of enlargement. Paper for Society for Music Theory Meeting, November 4, 1995
  - Alpern, Wayne, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    Minimum aggregate partitions: mapping timepoints in Babbitt's third and fourth string quartets. Paper for Society for Music Theory Meeting, November 2, 1996
  - Althius, Theo. A., 2000 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    Mathematical structures in atonal music. Master's thesis, Feb. 2000
  - Balzano, Gerald J., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    The group-theoretic description of 12-fold and microtonal pitch systems, In Computer Music Journal 4:4, Winter 1980
  - Balzano, Gerald J., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    The pitch set as a level of description for studying musical pitch perception, In Music, Mind, and Brain: the neuropsychology of music, 1982
  - Barbaud, Pierre, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    Vademecum de l'ingénieur en musique, 1993. Chapter 3. Triades at Accords
  - Bass, Richard, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    Half-diminished functions and transformations in late-Romantic music. Examples, 2000?
  - Berry, David Carson, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    The exclusion quotient. With correspondence.
  - Bier, Carol, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    Elements of plane symmetry in Oriental carpets, In Textile Museum Journal, 1992
  - Blau, Stephen K., 1999 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    The hexachordal theorem: a mathematical look at interval relations in twelve-tone composition, In Mathematics Magazine 72:4, Oct. 1999
  - Boge, Claire, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    Correspondence
  - Boge, Claire, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    Idea and analysis: aspects of unification in musical explanation, 1988
  - Boge, Claire, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    Poetic analysis and the musical experience. Paper presented at Music Theory Midwest Meeting, May 17, 1991
  - Bombieri, Enrico, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    Prime territory: exploring the infinite landscape at the base of the number system, In The Sciences, September/October 1992
  - Browne, Richmond, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    Tonal implications of the diatonic set, In In Theory Only 5:6-7, 1981
  - Buchler, Michael, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    An alternative to the interval-class vector and its use in relating abstract pitch-class sets. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, November 3, 1995
  - Buchler, Michael, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    A cycle-based system for relating pitch-class sets. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1997
  - Buchler, Michael, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    Scale-step sequences in tonal music. Paper presented at Music Theory Midwest Meeting, May 14, 1999
  - Cambouropoulos, Emilios, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    A general pitch interval representation: theory and applications. Reprint from Journal of New Music Research 25, 1996
  - Cambouropoulos, Emilios, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    Unscramble: a new unsupervised symbolic machine learning algorithm - excerpt. March 1997
  - Capuzzo, Guy, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    CUP spaces in post-tonal music. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, November 5, 2000
  - Capuzzo, Guy, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    Pitch space ordering types in the recent solo music of Elliott Carter. Paper presented at Music Theory Society of New York State Meeting, April 13, 1997
  - Carey, Norman, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    Correspondence, 1 item
  - Carey, Norman, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    Amarantha. Composition with correspondence
  - Carey, Norman, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    Coherence and failure: a general theory of ambiguity and contradiction. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, November 5, 2000
  - Carey, Norman, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    Generic ordering in well-formed scales. With correspondence
  - Carey, Norman, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    Illustrations for lecture, University at Buffalo, October 26, 1992
  - Carey, Norman, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    The ordering of generic intervals in well-formed scales.
  - Carey, Norman, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    Well-formed scales and the invariant generator.
  - Carey, Norman and Clampitt, David, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    Aspects of well-formed scales, In Music Theory Spectrum 11:2, 1989
  - Carey, Norman and Clampitt, David, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    Pythagorean scales and the Nicomachus triangle.
  - Carey, Norman and Clampitt, David, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    Regions: a theory of tonal spaces in early Medieval treatises.
  - Carey, Norman and Clampitt, David, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    Structural properties of musical scales.
  - Carey, Norman and Clampitt, David, undated (Box 7, Folder 118)
    Two theorems concerning rational approximations.
  - Chailley, J., 1960 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    Essai analytique sur la formation de l'octoechos latin, In Essays presented to Egon Wellesz, 1960
  - Chalmers, John H., 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - Chalmers, John H., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    Construction and harmonization of microtonal scales in non-twelve-tone equal temperaments. With copy in Italian
  - Chalmers, John H., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    Cyclic scales.
  - Chalmers, John H., undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
    Music and geometry.
  - Chalmers, John H., undated (Box 7, Folder 124)
    Tritriadic scales with seven tones.
  - Chalmers, John H., 1986 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    Tritriadic scales with seven tones, Part Two: derived forms and structural properties.
  - Chalmers, John H., undated (Box 7, Folder 126)
    Tritriadic scales with seven tones, Part Three: The M-T and D-M matrices
  - Chalmers, John H. and Wilson, Ervin M., 1982 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    Combination product sets and other harmonic and melodic structures.
  - Clampitt, David, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    Correspondence, 6 items
  - Clampitt, David, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    Correspondence with Richard Cohn and David Lewin, 3 items
  - Clampitt, David, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    Alternative interpretations of some measures from Parsifal.
  - Clampitt, David, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    Aspects of taxonomic and transformational music theories. Examples, March 16, 2000
  - Clampitt, David, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    Brahms paper. Fall 1999
  - Clampitt, David, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    Lumpiness is orthogonal to smoothness. Examples, March 18, 1992
  - Clampitt, David, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
    Maximally even sets summary
  - Clampitt, David, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    nlog23.
  - Clampitt, David, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    Notes on Pythagorean tuning and well-formed scales. 6 NOvember 1992
  - Clampitt, David, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    Ramsey theory, unary transformations, and Webern's op. 5, no. 4.
  - Clampitt, David, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    Recent diatonic theory and the Scholia Enchiriadis. October 1992
  - Clampitt, David, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    Riemann groups. 1 December 1996
  - Clampitt, David, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    Some refinements on the three gap theorem with applications to music. Paper presented at International Symposium on Music and Mathematics, May 29-30, 1994
  - Clampitt, David, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 141)
    Structural and transformational properties of pairwise well-formed scales. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, October 1997
  - Cohn, Richard, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    Correspondence, 4 items between Clough, Cohn, Jack Douthett, David Clampitt, and David Lewin; with other examples
  - Cohn, Richard, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 143)
    Brahms's complex hemiolas. October 1998
  - Cohn, Richard, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    Maximally smooth cycles, hexatonic systems, and the analysis of late-Romantic triadic progressions, In Music analysis 15:1, March 1996
  - Cohn, Richard, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    Metric and hypermetric dissonance in the Menuetto of Mozart's Symphony in G Minor, K. 550, In Intégral 6, 1993
  - Cohn, Richard, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 146)
    Music theory's new pedagogability, In Music Theory Online 4:2, 1998
  - Cohn, Richard, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    Neo-Riemannian operations, parsimonious trichords, and their Tonnetz representations, In Journal of Music Theory 41:1, 1997
  - Cohn, Richard, 1994-1998 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    The over-determined triad: a group-theoretic approach to chromatic harmony. Book prospectus, 1994, 1998
  - Cohn, Richard, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    P-related sets. With correspondence, including with Paul Ishihara
  - Cohn, Richard, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 150)
    Properties and generability of transpositionally invariant sets, In Journal of Music Theory 35, 1991
  - Cohn, Richard, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 151)
    Thematicized hemiolas, rhythmic normalization, and the metric consonance/dissonance metaphor. Examples for paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, October 18, 1992
  - Cohn, Richard, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    Transpositional combination of beat-class sets in Steve Reich's phase-shifting music (with earlier version), In Perpspectives of New Music 30:2, Summer 1992. Earlier working title: Teleology, craft, tradition, and analysis in a minimalist context: transpositional combination of beat-class sets in Steve Reich's phase-shifting music.
  - Corless, Robert M., 1992 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    Continued fractions and chaos, In American Mathematical Monthly 99:3, March 1992
  - Cuciurean, John, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 154)
    Properties of equal-tempered microtonal scales in Easley Blackwood's 12 Microtonal etudes, op. 28.. 14 December 1994
  - Dembski, Stephen, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 155)
    Steps and skips from content and order: aspects of a generalized step-class system. With correspondence (1 item) to Clough.
  - Derrick, William; Eidswick, Jack, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 156)
    Continued fractions, Chebychev polynomials, and chaos, In American Mathematical Monthly 102:4, April 1995
  - Douthett, Jack, 1989-1999 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    Correspondence and miscellaneous notes, 18 items
  - Douthett, Jack, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 158)
    Correspondence on Knuth problem
  - Douthett, Jack, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    Correspondence on Pn relations
  - Douthett, Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 160)
    An approach to ETS theory. Lecture notes